All right here it comes
my other favorite section that is tools
you know I own something
like 50/60 lifetime licenses
and I partner with a lot of these guys
back in the days when I was running the agency so
I've seen it all I tested them all for just for
fun at the beginning then it became the job and
I built infrastructures that go from like
just a bunch of emails a day to
managing 20 to 30 thousand
lits a month so I will help
you with the framework and you will
see that attached there is the
guide that I wrote for for another startup
about tools so you can download that and find
them yeah an additional more in-depth guide about
what we are seeing today so let's go
with the mistakes so the mistakes is basically
you're feeding your in your kid when it comes to tools at
least that's what happens with me flashing lights
we chase features because we get promised that
there is this database that works particularly well
but guys sales and software are two different things
you can do just fine and well enough
in the early days with the CRM and a
structured sales playbook and perhaps I'll tell
you later on what the sales playbook is or
if you are at the point where
you need to scale you must consider
quite about quite a few things so let's
move on and see as I was mentioning
you have a good market so when you're validating you're validating
you don't need much but when you're scaling you need
to think how can I scale how many lits
do I need so I need basically and we'll see that
in the last chapter how to reverse engineer
that so we will think it this way we'll
think I will convert 5-10%
of user coming down to demo
I need a scalable system that books me 10%
of the meeting the emails that I send
out how many prospects do I need and
within this which channels
do I use do I need to integrate with the CRM how
use how easy is that okay so
and all the other things so we go
into the tool evaluation phase now there
are kind of three main set of tools that
I would like to talk to you about the first
and the easiest one for you especially in the early
begin and early phase is an all-around tool
like for instance one of the
most famous is Apollo obviously you you
have a tool that is a database but also you can send
a bunch of emails and you can do a bunch of outreach actions
then you have LinkedIn only tools
you have email only tools phone only tools
and multi-channel tools that don't have a database
so perhaps you on in these tools you can
build the side of actions so that go from LinkedIn
to to email but you need to feed in
your database within that then you
have databases okay so
databases you can either
find them online so for instance
you're selling to hotels you can find hotels databases
online or you can scrape them okay so you can scrape
data in many ways you remember we're talking communities we
were talking in the impose there are actually tools that
will allow you to scrape certain posts on
LinkedIn or other social medias and do outreach
on these exact people so you can be specifically on point
because they fit your ICP within
that case you will need an
enrichment tool that kind of helps you out
filtering what data is good what data is not good so if
person from the company and they will
also give you the email address and other
couple data that then you can plug in
into your multi-channel tool
okay so these are the the three types ultimately you're
gonna need an outreach tool and you're gonna need some sort
of database if you're not going for an all-around solution but again
it depends on the go-to-market and the channels
so I prepared a few
example so let's say that you are a small
task selling as this small
task to load to your clients you need to
came on to the leads you're going email only you use app
spot so you need integration if you can manage
everything from there it's bonus point easy of
you so then I can hire junior staff for it
to be managed or a
VA virtual assistant and I
needed to be rolling out constant solutions
and I want to personalize the messages so
this is the features that I need so
listed from the variables and
so if also there is a benefit
to buying domains and buying email addresses directly
from them that that is a huge bonus point so I'm
going to be looking to be looking on the market
for something that fits these
exact needs okay instead
if I'm selling b2b SAS with high average
value of the leads and I need much lower
level but I need ease of use I need some kind
of BDR and prospecting that is a little bit more
on point with leads included I will go
for another round to that can enhance productivity
can go multi-channel can be integrated can have reporting
and yeah this is basically it
now there is a cheat sheet here
so there are a bunch of tools
that I already partnered with so for
around we have a polo chrono lamb list I'm giving
you a couple of automation tools that
are a little bit easier or a little bit
harder to learn it really depends on your high CP
and how on point you want to be and
yeah the stage of the the startup at
the beginning I usually recommend doing
structured work so even with the
with the support of the SAS but really do things manually so you
can learn all along the way the more you learn the
more you'll find a tool that really fits you to a
glove and and
yeah if you have questions about these tools let me know but also
again I'll be sharing my guide
so the key takeaways for this are
go to market rules so numbers will see the
next lesson the absolutely 100% rule
and scalable so we need to think limits of course
if we are handling cold calling we need x
amount of people same for LinkedIn profile so same
for email which you will need eventually domains
and x amount of email per domains and yeah so
you need to think about this when you're picking
up a tool and of course it has to be effective I don't
know again it depends on the stage you here so if
you really have a CRM or if you're really setting up an autonomy
automations we tools like make albato and then
and such so of course you need some kind
of flexibility from the perspective
okay so next up we will see we
will see the operational side
of it so track APIs and all the kind of stuff
and so yeah see you next