Hey guys, welcome to module 3.
IACP will deep dive into the customer profile
this time. We'll see all the ins and outs and offsets.
Now, before we start, let's start again with the mistakes because
stop selling everyone is a concept that
I want to endorse each and every time because
the more bigger the list and the more
variable will be your offering
and your copywriting, the less learnings,
the less meaningful learnings we can make. So if I
have a set amount of variables like
any problem in math problem, you can change
the variables and make learnings and then find the winning path. So we
will do the exact same from the
perspective of the people.
We are going to use the exact same frameworks that we used from
the previous chapter. So it's going to be really simple
from this standpoint. Now, from the demographic perspective,
I want to have one bit on the side that will help
me set the tone with this person and the other thing will
help me, the thing on the right, so the job
title, location, company, site and so on. That will help me
find a set of people when I'm going to use a database
or when I'm going to do scraping or whatever that is that we will do
later. We can use them as filters. So
it's important that this stuff is kind of standardized from CS Navigator
or other tools that you might use to do a
little bit of market research. So it will look
something like this. So it's going to be important,
the company size and the first bit I know from the
company data, but also it's important for me the interest and the
touch point that she has on. We'll
see how to put that to use. The other bit that I want to
spend a little bit of time is the jobs to be done
because it's a really important framework
because it will help us frame the problem,
the outcome and the trigger in a much more
relevant way. Because I know, for example,
that the jobs to be done, my target CEO
of a pre-seed startup right now needs to improve the
sales team or has sales inconsistency or it
has a low growth rate. These are all triggers I can use in copyrighted.
The same triggers I know want to
look for something. So I know what they're
looking for. And I know the
outcome. So let me see. If
they are able to sell more, this course really helps them
to sell more because of X, Y, Z, they'll be able to release stress
from inconsistency and focus on what matters
most. So my first intro could
be, A, do you feel your time could be optimized?
Okay, so that doesn't lead to sale, but it gives me an opening,
but we'll see that later again. Then the four forces.
This is important for the offering to
actually add extra spice to how bad our
customer problem situation is. How good is our solution?
What kind of anxiety they might have or how we can detach
from the status quo because a lot of people might be attached to the
status quo. They don't even want to change. So how
can we change that? So this is
another example. So a lot of stress for growth
and lack of time to create frameworks. That's all that we
ask funders struggle. So that's why we try to find templates
and they don't actually fit because templates are templates
and not frameworks. You can plug them in anywhere you want.
That's why I'm giving you frameworks. So you can plug them in
anywhere you want, whether you're using Ocean, Gera, Trello,
whatever. How good is the solution? And then again,
anxiety and attachment to the status quo.
All these bits will come later on at use. The
others are the touch points. So I know that Julia
listened to B2B Group podcast. She's part of the
female tech funders. And so that is, for instance,
a touch point that I can later on
use. So this is just a little
recap of our ICP. So I
have it clear. So I'll share the framework for you.
So once you've done everything, you can fill this in and you're
going to have your personas right there. The other
thing are the touch points. So that's the
trigger spit. For instance, we said
that she likes podcasts. So we can send the first message
reaching out about the latest episode of XYZ podcast
that we know she follows. Or we could do an app bank campaign
using that exact podcast as a touch point. Hey,
have you ever listened to this podcast?
They're talking about really interesting stuff about
sales. And then you can see if the prospects is
interested or not. So you can use a lot
of things like this. So accelerator pages
like LinkedIn pages. You can use meta communities to see
what people are talking about. You can use Slack communities
and you can gather these additional touch points and then
find the same people on LinkedIn. And then do a Taylor
campaign on exactly that. So this
is what will give you actually the superpowers.
Okay, because you can make a lot of a lot of different
things from the perspective standpoint here.
Now, do you remember mapping? Last time we talked
about tearing and mapping, the one thing
that I suggest you and recommend you for
each and every people, especially the bigger sales
you do is to not only to map out the buying committee,
but also to understand what are their concerns,
what are their goals, how they may
block you. So you can have content
later on that is preset and ready.
Or when you already do the demo or when you already this
happened to me when you already made the first phone
call, they say, oh, no, but we don't put in
beverage service. I was reaching out to the basketball
teams and they were the first thing that they were saying to me,
oh, no, we don't manage the thing. And my answer
was preset. I know and I'm aware of it,
but I would like to have your endorsement before I go to the food and beverage manager.
And then they were willing to talk to
me because they knew that I had an interest
in them. So these kind of things
will help you really understand
the buying committee and will help you prepare
stuff in advance so your sales cycle actually
doesn't get out of your hands.
So the key takeaways of this module and I hope everything
was clear because we covered a lot of things. Again,
segmentation leads to scalability variables. If
you can find touch points, you can be relevant
and I again, please do a lot of it.
Based a lot of your route bound on triggers and contents
and communities and stuff before you find your path
to scale and dynamic. So I see peace change
things change. Think about the shift of AI now.
Everything is changing with this. So everything is dynamic.
So I see peace will change and buying committees
will change. So please update everything.
If you don't want to do it every six months, every year,
let's say something like this. Okay. Now it's
your turn to pick tier design and SAP and try
to map out the company and stuff. And
I will see you for the next module.
Ciao. [BLANK_AUDIO]