Here we go, guys. Welcome to module
4: Content that Converts.
There is no campaign without content. I'll make you
a ton of examples, but by that
I mean assets for your company that
will make the sales process helpful
or also hooks for the prospects that we
can use to gather feedback or to sell a product
or something. So let's start as per usual with
the mistakes. Again: stop selling,
but start helping. Validation will
be the answer. We'll see
everything later, but most of the time, when I've
seen SDRs at the higher level or even at the beginning,
again, we were just sending an email, selling a feature.
At best, it was a PDF, and that was it. So
that PDF was actually content built
for inbound. So again, we have to be relevant
here. What are we doing? Okay, so it's better
to have no content than bad content at all. But
we'll see how, with a little effort, we can
create something together. And the other thing
is that no journey was designed, so meaning
what does this person need to know at this specific point?
Because when you buy a TV, when you buy software, when
you buy anything, you will learn bit by
bit what you need to know. What you're
buying it for the vision, what kind of size
for the light you have in the room, what should
be the contrast, and so on. So you learn everything bit by bit, and
everything should be the same for prospecting.
So we'll see how to do this with three simple frameworks.
The first is what I call "user type." It's not really a framework.
We'll see. The second one is the lead generation template,
so we'll design the journey, and then we'll do a little bit
of positioning and brand positioning as the
last bit. So the first thing
is my prospect, the person
that I just described. Is my
CEO aware or not aware of the problem? And
is that person aware or not aware of the solution?
So my personal target from this
example is solution aware, because
they're trying to improve sales. Most of them are
trying to build something or they're trying to improve. So
they are my target, and my content should
be focused on that specific niche, which
doesn't mean "what is an outbound tool?"
That's not an article that I'm going
to write. But I can write a guide like
this with this specific framework. So
you will have to understand if your target persona
is problem aware, problem unaware, or solution
aware, so you can decide where to focus on in terms of content.
And that will make you more relevant, and that will
make you more attractive and appealing.
Then we have to do the lead generation template,
as I was explaining before. Where does the journey
start? Where does my CEO try
to understand more about sales, about creating
a go-to-market strategy, about creating a lead generation
strategy, which tools to use? So where do they
start? What then do they need to learn
about my product? And what will affect
the discovery and decision making?
That is incredibly important. And as an example,
my CEO will talk to ChatGPT, Google. They will most
likely use LinkedIn. It could be a lot of
communities, as we've seen before, and they will look for frameworks,
tools, inspiration, case studies, and LinkedIn influencers.
So they will start learning from there. Then they will
see case studies and a growing need for structure because they
might have tried something, but they didn't get results, blah, blah,
blah, blah. So this person is moving
on a journey that eventually will help
you convert them. And all along the way,
the more you have bits in your copywriting or the
more you have bits in your landing pages. So I meant content
goes everywhere. This goes on your landing
page, that goes in your FAQ, that goes in the PDF,
that goes in the video. Because if you make
clear to them, for instance, that this course
is going to be free always for pre-seed startups,
and it's done, right there within the decision making,
I potentially removed the blocker of the pricing.
Do you know what I mean? So this is going to be
really important for you. Okay, so you're
going to see this last little problem. I spent
a lot of time on this. Then that's your
turn now. Build your content. I want you to build
the content for the awareness phase, the discovery phase, and the conversion
phase. Just an idea and a track.
Not the whole thing, unless you do have it already,
and do the frameworks. But I will make
you examples of what kind of content
I mean, so you can be creative.
From the awareness perspective, for instance, if you're trying to sell software or something,
you can interview five experts and publish a blog article.
That's some kind of content you can also use in your lead
generation strategy, by interviewing the
person or using the blog article as something that can
help the people.
Discovery. I could potentially build
a tool page on my website and link the people in
and use it as something that I can attract people
to. This stuff goes a lot on
LinkedIn. And also conversion. Again, we
can write a blog case study, make a video on YouTube
or a webinar with the client that we can also use.
These are examples. Please try to fill out the
journey and try to build one piece of content for each.
And you can do it. Key takeaways.
Pause on that.
Journey. It's important that you design the journey. It's important
that you design the entry point. The more you design it, the more relevant you'll
be with your copywriting. The more effective will be the campaign.
The more effective will be your marketing
overall. And assets. Again, try
to use assets that are reusable and
scalable. Or if they're not scalable, for instance,
you have to interview a person, well, that has high value.
So that's fine. Okay, so that's
it. Going back: bonus
time, because you can add this
to additional things. So
building content with using traditional frameworks.
So this will help you position your brand and
make an understanding of where to place
yourself in the market. So for instance, if
you're low paying, like vitamins, you will
need to have a lot of content that is selling
the benefits of the vitamins.
But on the other perspective, if you're a painkiller and you have a headache,
I will just go to a pharmacy and buy one.
So that doesn't need educational content.
If you move the toggles here and there,
you will understand what kind of effort
to put in the content, for who, and
when, and who to sell to. And the other
thing: you can build content, as I mentioned,
one for awareness, one for blah, blah, blah,
the previous scheme. You can use this additional scheme.
If you like it, I really like it because it gives
me, when I ask myself questions, a lot of
answers, thinking about the prospect. So you can use this
as a guide because it will help you understand why
your product is helpful but not essential. So we'll
try to switch the perspective and make it essential. We'll
try to find the best showcase, and that's pretty important.
And eventually, you can build offer amplifiers. So you can
have the cherry on the pie. Okay.
Next, we'll puzzle everything up
and do some copywriting together.
So I hope you're excited because we are moving towards the,
we are actually just past the mid-chapter of it.
If you have any questions, let me know. Otherwise, I'll see you next time. [BLANK_AUDIO]