Alright guys, welcome to module 2,
ICP. I'll split this into two parts. You're going
to see the company side of it and the people side of
it in the module 3. I don't want to dip it dive because
it's really important because I see most people
selling everyone and it doesn't matter.
They try to sell me the thing but oh yeah, but I selected
software development companies 51 to
200 and I sent them my best offer but I didn't get replaced.
Guys, you need to be relevant today.
We're bumped constantly with ads. We are bumped constantly with everything
and sales is another channel that is also an annoying
one. Unless you decide to
make things a little bit different,
you're not going to cut through the noise. It's impossible.
We need to take all this and we need to take all this
now because this happens both to pre-seed startups but also to people
that already have a sales process that is probably working
than the one that the course is proposing. But sometimes
the campaigns go up and down so you need to refresh
your point of view or you need to find something different. We'll
see how to find something different here from the company perspective.
We're going to use three frameworks. The one is the demographics, the second one
is triggers and the third one is tiering. With
the first one, we're going to see all the company's data that we
need. The triggers are going to identify something that can help be more
relevant and with the third one, we will avoid getting
out of our minds because it's taking too long
just to sell one single thing. We'll see the concept
of tiering. Now, before we even begin with
the first framework, remember you're never
selling to one single person. You're going to have a champion
that is the person that is going to push you. You're going to have the
decision maker that will sign the agreement. It could be the
same as the champion. But you might also have an influencer, somebody
that you can also get in touch with. You might have a person
that is reluctant to do anything. So you need to
tackle that when you sell. And you have
a gatekeeper, so somebody that might actually can
get the food and the door for
you. It's really important that you understand this
because we have to convey this in copyrighted messaging and content later
on. Now, without further ado, filmographics. What
I want to see is something like this.
I want to have enough detailed
data but not too small.
Meaning that I'm going into, say, as
a navigator Apollo and I'm trying to
find startups, to five millions with that
company headcount. And I try to narrow it down
when I have a batch of two to five thousand.
So then I can make the campaign scalable. But if
I go below two thousand, that
might be too small. So I might go up. So this is
a flexible scheme so you can add things
or you can remove things. But Bullpark five thousand,
three five thousand, it's good range for scaling
campaigns. So that is really important
for you to do there and how to do it
right. Then triggers. We might find
out that there are some triggers, some updates that are
really good. So some of them could be just
related to the timeline that they have. Or about
social media updates that they publish.
So if they are preparing an event, I can get in touch because
I can send my software for the event. So if I'm
going to a conference, that's another
way of doing an outbound based on triggers.
So you cannot just manage triggers there and they will look like this.
So if there is any useful update, they are
hiring a new sales member or they are
closing more clients. Or you don't see
that they are closing clients. There could be some kind of trigger.
So please identify them and make good use of them.
Whether you are in the first sales part or whether you're in
the most advanced bit where you're doing more
BDR kind of job. This is going to be really
helpful for you. Then tiering.
Without going nuts, you can sell to anybody
at the same time or with the same timeline. You
always want to go for Wales, but unless you know how
to sell them, unless you know the pain points of the
blocker in the buying committee, because they might block you there,
you're going to waste a lot of time in a sales cycle.
So what we have to do is we have to keep in mind that
there are some deals that will be fast and this will
be medium. Some deals will be long. So we need to build the outbound
campaigns within this ratio and within your company's
goals so we can avoid losing our mind
and manage the sales pipeline and the
campaigns properly. For us,
like for the example, it would be a pre-seed startup that
would be the easy sale, but the seed startup might take long because they have
more people, longer adoption, more proof needed, better social
proof and the Wales that I know is going to take three months. I will
decide when to reach out and I can move
on with that. Now the key takeaways are the ones
in my voice. Target structure, okay.
Segmentation leads to scalability because when we find out
what works for that specific segment, we can then scale
the campaigns. Entry points will help you cut through
the noise. So really key and we'll see later on also
with the personal standpoint how to do it with communities
and other channels and target priorities.
So you can balance it out so you can start reaching out to Wales while
you try to close fast deals with postpone the intermediate because
it also depends on the tools and the amount
of time you have for this. But we'll see also
that later on. If you have any questions, shout out. Otherwise,
I'll see you in a minute or two. It's now your turn.
[BLANK_AUDIO]