Hello everyone, welcome to chapter
5, Kobe writing now. This
is one of my favorites because I will
try to challenge you deeply on this.
So let's see the mistakes that we see usually
when trying to do lead generation. So
people usually sound like really salesy,
"A we do this and this, that we provide you this, would
you..." blah blah blah. Okay, it's annoying.
Or sometimes you see the novels, but
the end thing is that they all sound a little bit
spammy, unpersonalized and yeah, it
just doesn't work. So I want you to make
a deal with me, would you be up for it just
for two weeks? So we'll try to take a different approach.
We will try to validate something instead
of trying to sell it. Okay, I'll make
a tough example on a SaaS and we'll see how we
can take this, but I would like you to test for your next
campaign validating and we'll see what that means in a second.
Check my hand. Okay, let's
go. So I write my goal for my perspective
action. So what I want to do
with my CEO, I want to understand
if they're trying to build a
sales playbook, to build a lead generation strategy,
to build the go to market strategy so I can help
them. And I can try ways to try
to find ways to ask them these specific
questions without being salesy.
Because if I'm salesy, they will never do
me a referral. But if I ask something
kindly and nicely, then I could always
say, well, do you know anybody who needs
this? Okay. As
simple as
that.
We might start up like we made the first two deals like this.
Okay. So no sales understanding, trying
to build a relationship and there is no I, we do this,
we do this, we do this, we do this. It's about the
prospect always. 100% of the time.
Okay. Now we're going to see a couple
of frameworks as per usual. So the channels, obviously
that's super important. The corporate writing frameworks, if
you don't know, there are a lot of frameworks like IEDAPAS, FAP,
4PDS, they're all different. So it's ways of,
it's their frameworks. So it's ways of explaining
something and leading to the path of the journey that the
user is supposed to make. And we'll
see the timeline, obviously by tier. Now coming to the
channel, mail, it's really important to be able to cut the noise.
So we have to be different. LinkedIn and communities
always relationship first and phone really clear,
quick and structured. Now about how to test
the channel, I would recommend you like every
two to four weeks to try to change channel,
starting with what you design with the IEDAPAS.
So with my CEO will be LinkedIn first and email
second, but then I could also try LinkedIn
only or email only or the both
of them. So then I know what and how
I can scale stuff because like email is more
scalable of course than LinkedIn, phone is less
scalable. So we need to find
the best way to do it and to
find a window. So it's a process
that is always ongoing. Now as an example of a framework
we got IEDAPAS, so we need to attract the user first,
stimulate the interest, then spark desire and ask
them to perform an action and to do this we're
going to be using LinkedIn and email.
Now something really personal, this is my personal
flow. What I actually do is sit down and
write this stuff by hand before I
design each campaign and everything
pretty much is a recap so it helps me
bring back the memories. Or the
most important thing to me is this last question,
what would you tell this person if you were
to meet at the bar during an industry
event? So this is usually my opening
because I want to start a conversation.
Now we are going to make a different
example. So we are targeting wealth,
we are a SaaS, we do AI research so it's a little
bit more complicated than the free
school for founders and we're going
to use the customer interview as
a hook. The goal is for us to validate if
they do market research with AI and the target is wealth.
So the first thing I'll try to get the interview, then
I'll try to build trust and showcase the benefit, then
I'll interview follow up and then I'll make the offer and
I'll use LinkedIn and email as channels.
So writing everything down, I'm targeting the
marketing is my ICP, they need more research
data, I interviewed them together, their knowledge, if they're really
using it, how they're benefiting at this,
I can offer them a POC at cost if they want
to try the platform. These are the outcomes
and the question I would ask AI is disrupting
the industry, what is your take
on that? And I can also within
this feed POC, sorry feed a demo of the
platform somehow. So if I were to write this
person, the first message would be about qualification
and notice you've been at the marketing for quite a few years,
must have been a rally, especially now that AI kicked
in and did this, okay, and changed
the way we do market research. Actually
I reached out about an interviews,
mind if I share a bit more, so I'm
not being too much. Then moving
to step two, I would try to build trust
and spark interest saying, well, I'm
a tail, this is my job title that of course
is relevant and we work on AI market research
and we are running this kind of
interview because relevant because
AI disrupted the way we do this,
now we can achieve this in that.
Would you be willing to take an interview on this?
Are you already working with AI? Are you
already market, are you seeing these benefits?
Because I'm showcasing this and I also want to see
if this person is already using one of my competitors
because if not, okay, that's one really
big point for us. Then I'll write the email
in case they don't get back to me on LinkedIn.
We are wrapping up so I can add the urgency,
we are wrapping up the interviews since
AI short interviews and marketing
are saying this to achieve this.
If you're willing to share your expertise, we love you to join the
other 25 experts so we are adding a little
bit of social proof. The last email,
again, we didn't sell anything because we don't know
if we are the right solution for them
and this is the right prospect
for us. Today is the last shot to be part
of the study. Perhaps you are not already
into AI so we can use something that triggers
them emotionally because if not,
this is the thing. Did you check out
our website? There is a video right there. So this doesn't
embarrass anyone. They can take a look, it's quick. They
can just type a link so we can get a user
on our site and that is the exact begin
of the journey that we planned
from awareness to conversion.
Moving on, timeline and triggering, of course,
the same applies to triggers. Some of them are
quicker, some of them are not. We made the hardest one.
I made a lot of examples on the first and on the second.
We made the hardest one because that is
something that needs to be a little bit
oiled first. Key takeaways, validate,
don't sell. You shook my hand. Don't forget about
that. It's always for them and you can be
a lot creative here because a lot happens,
a lot of people have a lot of interest and of course they have a
lot of goals. So if you understand if these are the goals, you
can be creative and you can build a lot of things. And
the last thing I want to tell you is test, test, test. Try to change
angles. Try to, if you're doing cold email, spin taxing
or liquid syntax where you can change the sentences
according to stuff. Take a look into it
and test a lot of things. They'll be testing,
you probably know if not you can ask.
I will see you next time with tools
and your turn. [BLANK_AUDIO]